# UZOAGULU JOSHUA

<u>uzoagulujoshua@yahoo.com</u> | (+234)7012318901 | <u>LinkedIn Profile</u> Wumba Apo, Abuja 90010

#### **PROFILE**

Organized, dedicated and ambitious budding professional with excellent attention to detail, and thirst for learning. interested in working closely with experienced developers. I have a lot of experience working with backend development tools like node.js, typescript, and express.js, and also with non-relational databases like MongoDB. I have experience deploying APIs on Digital Ocean, Namecheap, and Heroku, including physical servers using Raspberry Pi

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### August 2022-Present

Junior Backend Developer, Namek Solutions

- Managed efficient NoSQL queries and data transport.
- Built APIs and data clients to consume APIs.
- Integrated third-party APIs from external applications into web platforms.
- Implemented robust security and data protection measures.
- Used Domain driven design architecture for API development with Typescript.
- Collaborated with multidisciplinary team of designers, developers and system administrators.

## February 2022-August 2022

Backend Developer Intern, Namek Solutions

- Cooperated with front-end developers and other team members to design more cohesive and functional code.
- Assisted project manager to prepare implementation plan from technical perspective.
- Designed, developed and tested software applications.

#### **EDUCATION**

University Of Nigeria Nsukka, Enugu, Nigeria November 2016 – June 2021: Bachelor of Science in Computer Science.

## **KEY SKILLS AND CHARACTERISTICS**

· Typescript/JavaScript

· Docker · Jest

· Node.js · MongoDB

· Express.js · Swagger docs

· React.js · Jest

· Vue.js · PostgreSQL

## **ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS**

Enterprise Blockchain, Hyperledger Aries, Hyperledger Fabric, art, Football, travel

Kubernetes